# **Ahmed Saed Mohamed**

# **DevOps Engineer**

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 2+ years of related experience.



## **Work History**

### 2022-05 -Current

### Full Stack Developer (Mentor)

FikirCamp, Hargeisa

- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans.
- Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.
- Worked with back-end developers to design APIs.
- Developed unit test cases for testing and automation.
- Used NodeJS, ORM and SQL/No-SQL to develop and manage databases.
- Analyzed existing software implementations to identify areas requiring improvement.
- Mentored junior members and delivered training to boost team skills set.
- Actively listened to customers, handled concerns quickly and escalated major issues to supervisor.

## 2021-08 -2022-03

# **IT Support Consultant**

WAAPO, Hargeisa

 Provided Tier 1 IT support to non-technical internal users through desk side support services.



## Contact

#### **Address**

Hargeisa

#### **Phone**

+252-633046457

#### Website

https://ahmedmohammad.netlify.app/

#### E-mail

ahmetmohamet281@gmail.com



## **Technical Profile**

- NodeJS
- MySQL & MS-SQL
- JavaScript
- PHP
- REACTJS
- NETWORKING AND SECURITY
- HTML CSS
- TAILWINDCSS



## Competencies

Application development

Concept development

Project Management

- Resolved diverse range of technical issues across multiple systems and applications for customers and end-users across various time zones.
- Submitted service tickets for equipment maintenance requests.
- Identified potential sales and cross-selling opportunities and informed supervisor.
- Provided documentation on troubleshooting of technical processes to support desk staff.

# 2021-01 - Network Technician Intern

2021-03

Somtel, Hargeisa

- Provided network support and performed troubleshooting to resolve various WAN/LAN connectivity issues.
- Installed and maintained data and voice circuits through routers, switches and WAN devices.
- Advanced knowledge of large-scale global enterprise network operations and security.
- Demonstrated proficiency in Linux, virtual platforms and cloud connectivity.

# **Education**

### 2020-10 -Current

# Bachelor of Science: Information Technology

Admas University - Hargeisa



Cisco Certified Network Assiociate CCNA 200-301

Fortinet NSE(1,2)

Introduction to IoT

CompTIA Network+ N10-0007

Software applications
Programming
Testing and maintenance